Alberto Roque Carrizo Fernández

contact@roquec.com | roquec.com | github.com/roquec | linkedin.com/in/roquec

Introduction

I am an experienced software engineer with a pragmatic approach, valuing simplicity in solutions. Highly independent and adept at self-learning, I seek opportunities to deliver genuine value to clients and society.

Skills

.NET C# Azure SQL Elasticsearch Git JavaScript Docker Microservices GQL SASS Powershell

Experience

2018-2022 | Senior Backend Engineer at NEOCLES (.NET, C#, SQL, Elasticsearch, Azure)

- Developed high-performance e-commerce APIs for thousands of concurrent users.
- Managed releases and maintenance for 5 segregated client production environments.
- Developed backend services receiving 10M+ import messages daily from external systems.
- Led upgrade and configuration of 30+ Elasticsearch servers, saving thousands of euros monthly.
- Worked directly with clients conducting fit-gap analyses to integrate new services.

2017-2018 | Fullstack Developer at INVESTEL (AngularJS, C#, SQL, .NET Framework)

- Led development of an AngularJS management application for internal use.
- Worked with designer on implementation of new Angular frontend for existing application.
- Evolved into a fullstack developer role, implementing new features and addressing backend bugs.
- Implemented and documented OAuth service for external client authentication.

Projects

2022-Present | Ship Navigation Application (WinUI3, C#, .NET)

- Designed and build Windows desktop application based on clients requirements.
- Integrated with Automatic Identification Systems (AIS) via serial port connection.

2023 | Portfolio Website: roquec.com (Jekyll, JavaScript, SASS, GitHub Actions)

- Developed custom SASS styling to imitate Visual Studio Code look.
- Created JavaScript solution for smooth SPA-like state through page navigations.
- Automated deployments, Lighthouse testing and reporting using GitHub Actions and Powershell.

Education

2019 | Microsoft Exam AZ-400 Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions.

2011-2016 | Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering from University of Oviedo.

Languages

English | Full professional proficiency.

Spanish | Native.